Guide to the William Van Duyn Tobacco Advertisement Collection
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
William Van Duyn Tobacco Advertisement Collection
1898-2002
Ms Coll 20
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
46
(187 binders)
William Van Duyn, a former smoker, collected advertisements and news articles related to tobacco, especially to cigarette smoking. These include cigarette advertisements by company and brand; other forms of tobacco advertisements including billboards (photographs taken by Van Duyn), merchandise catalogs, and sponsorship of racing; and newspaper and magazine articles and ephemera related to the anti-smoking movement and tobacco regulation and litigation.
Van Duyn, William
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by William Van Duyn, 2002
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
This collection of magazine advertisements, ephemera, articles, and photographs, was begun in 1994 by William Van Duyn, then a resident of Voluntown, Connecticut, who became fascinated by the ubiquity and deceptiveness of tobacco advertisements as a byproduct of his own effort to quit smoking. In addition to collecting, he founded a website to help others to quit. Van Duyn organized his advertisements, etc. into labeled looseleaf binders with the overall title "Gnikoms!" for smoking spelled backwards. At the time of his gift, Van Duyn and his family were living in Guilford and about to move to Canada.
Scope and Contents
The first and main part of the collection contains cigarette advertisements from popular magazines arranged by tobacco company, brand, and year. The companies are those in business when Van Duyn was collecting (1994-2002), not the original nor current companies. Many advertisements in this section can be identified by magazine and date. Although the advertisements are predominantly from American companies, there are also advertisements of British and Continental brands. One can trace advertising campaigns by different companies in different eras. The second part of the collection contains advertisements for cigars and other forms of tobacco, examples of cigarette packaging, photographs by Van Duyn of billboards and other outdoor advertisements for cigarettes, images of cigarette sponsorship of auto racing and other sports, and advertisements in which smoking is used to promote other products. The third part of the collection includes magazine and newspaper articles on legislation limiting smoking, litigation against the tobacco companies, and the settlement of 1997 with state attorney-generals. There are anti-smoking brochures and advertisements from the American Cancer Society, the National Cancer Institute, the American Lung Association, and other organizations, and advertisements for products and methods to quit smoking.
Arrangement
Organized into two series, Regular and Oversize. Each series is subdivided into three subseries: 1. Magazine advertisements for cigarettes by brand. 2. Other tobacco advertisements. 3. Anti-smoking movement and tobacco politics.
Advertising -- Cigarettes; Advertising, Magazine; Advertising -- Tobacco; Antismoking movement -- United States; Cigarettes; Smoking; Tobacco; Photographs; Sheet music; American Cancer Society; American Council on Science and Health; American Lung Association; American Tobacco Company; Brown & Williamson; INFACT (Firm); Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company; P. Lorillard Company; Philip Morris and Company; R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company; Tobacco Institute (Washington, D.C.); United States. Federal Trade Commission
- Regular size, Series I
  - Magazine advertisements for cigarettes by brand, Subseries 1
    Scope and Contents
    Organized by company, brand, and date. See Series 2, Oversize, for additional advertisements of many of the brands below. Tobacco companies were those existing between 1994 and 2002, the years of Van Duyn's collecting.
    - American Tobacco Company (Brown & Williamson): (Herbert) Tareyton, Malibu, Colony, Half and Half, Bull Durham, American Lights, Montclair, Iceberg, Maryland 00's, Riviera, Silva Thins, Long Johns, Tall, 1916-1995 (Box 1)
      On Tareytown, see also oversize binder 130.
    - Brown & Williamson (The American Tobacco Company): Lucky Strike, 1917-1987 (Box 2)
      For Lucky Strike, see also oversize binders 133-135.
    - Brown & Williamson: Lucky Strike, 1996-2001 (Box 3)
    - Brown & Williamson: Carlton, 1963-1994 (Box 4)
    - Brown & Williamson: Carlton, 1995-1999 (Box 5)
    - Brown & Williamson: Kool., 1930-1984 (Box 6)
      For Kool, see also oversize binders 131-132.
    - Brown & Williamson: Kool, 1984-1997 (Box 7)
    - Brown & Williamson: Kool, 1997-2001 (Box 8)
    - Brown & Williamson: Misty, 1990-2001 (Box 9)
    - Brown & Williamson: Raleigh, Bel-Air, Wings, Fact, Arctic Lights (Box 10)
    - Brown & Williamson: Pall Mall, 1914-2001 (Box 11)
    - Brown & Williamson: Viceroy, Barclay, Richland, GPC (Box 12)
    - Brown & Williamson: Capri, 1987-1999 (Box 13)
    - Liggett & Myers: L&M, Lark, Adam, Eve, Decade, Stride, Pyramid, Oasis. (Box 14)
    - Liggett & Myers: Chesterfield, Omni (Box 15)
      For Chesterfield, see also oversize binders 140-141
    - P. Lorillard: Newport, 1960-1996 (Box 16)
      For Newport, see also oversize binder 144.
    - P. Lorillard: Newport, 1997-2002; Newport Stripes, 1986-1999, 1986-2002 (Box 17)
    - P. Lorillard: Kent, Golden Lights (Box 18)
    - P. Lorillard: Beech-Nut, True, Triumph, Century Great Lengths, Max, Twist, Satin, Spring, Style., 1942-1997 (Box 19)
    - P. Lorillard: Helmar, Rameses, Egyptian Deities, Mecca, Murad, Old Gold, 1913-1993 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous. brands: Fatima, WDC Triangle Pipes, Melachrino, Pet Cigarettes, Mogul, Spud, Fifty-Six, Milo, Velvet, Nestor, Vogue, Domino, Chelsea, Regent, King Sano, Sherman's, Dunhill, Gauloises, Cartier, Springwater, Calume, Djarum, Sampoerna, Rave, Natural American Spirit. (Box 21)
    - Philip Morris: Basic, 1993-2001 (Box 22)
    - Philip Morris: Merit, 1976-1985 (Box 23)
    - Philip Morris: Merit, 1985-1992 (Box 24)
    - Philip Morris: Merit, 1993-2000 (Box 25)
    - Philip Morris: Virginia Slims, 1969-1982 (Box 26)
      For Virginia Slims, see also oversize binder 156.
    - Philip Morris: Virginia Slims, 1983-1989 (Box 27)
    - Philip Morris: Virginia Slims, 1990-1995 (Box 28)
    - Philip Morris: Virginia Slims, 1996-1999 (Box 29)
    - Philip Morris: Virginia Slims, 1999-2000 (Box 30)
    - Philip Morris: English Ovals, Philip Morris, (Benson & Hedges) Multifilter, Next, Saratoga, Cambridge, Galaxy, Alpine, Bucks, 1934-2000 (Box 31)
    - Philip Morris: Benson & Hedges, 1960-1976 (Box 32)
      For Benson & Hedges, see also oversize binder 147.
    - Philip Morris: Benson & Hedges, 1977-1990 (Box 33)
    - Philip Morris: Benson & Hedges, 1990-1999 (Box 34)
    - Philip Morris: Parliament, 1950-1999 (Box 35)
      For Parliament, see also oversize binder 156.
    - Philip Morris: Parliament, 1999-2002 (Box 36)
    - Philip Morris: Players, 1983–1988; Players Navy Cut, 1996, 1983-1996 (Box 37)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1937-1950, 1955-1979 (Box 38)
      For Marlboro, see also oversize binders 149-155.
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1980-1985 (Box 39)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1986-1988 (Box 40)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1989-1993 (Box 41)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1994-1996 (Box 42)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1997-1998 (Box 43)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1998-1999 (Box 44)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1999-2000 (Box 45)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 2000-2001 (Box 46)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro (international) (Box 47)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Cavalier, Real, Bright, Sterling, Ritz, Chelsea, Magna. (Box 48)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Now, 1976-1993 (Box 49)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Doral, 1970-1998 (Box 50)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Doral, 1998-2002 (Box 51)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Camel, ca. 1920-1974 (Box 52)
      For Camel, see also oversize binders 159-163.
    - R. J. Reynolds: Camel, 1974-1983 (Box 53)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Camel, 1988-1997 (Box 54)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Camel, 1997-2000 (Box 55)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Camel --Bar and music promotions, 1997-2000 (Box 56)
      Beginning of binder includes "Camel Roadhouse Tour" events for motorcyclists.
    - R. J. Reynolds: Vantage, 1971-1990 (Box 57)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Kamel. 1996–2000; Moonlight Tobacco Co. Brands: Metro Slim Lights, Sedona, Jumbos, City, North Star, Politix. (Box 58)
      For Kamel, see also oversize binder 164.
    - R. J. Reynolds: Winston, 1955-1982 (Box 59)
      For Winston, see also oversize binders 167-169.
    - R. J. Reynolds: Winston, 1982-1997 (Box 60)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Winston, 1997-1998 (Box 61)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Winston, 1998-1999 (Box 62)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Winston, 2000-2002 (Box 63)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Salem, ca. 1960-1994 (Box 64)
      For Salem, see also oversize binders 165-166.
    - R. J. Reynolds: Salem, 1997-1999 (Box 65)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Salem, 1999-2000 (Box 66)
    - R. J. Reynolds: More, 1974-1989 (Box 67)
    - United Kingdom and Canadian brands, 1898-1990s (Box 68)
      Ogden's, Craven "A", Minor, Player's, Du Maurier, State Express 555, Greys, Wills Three Castles, Passing Clouds, John Cotton, Marcovitch Black & White, Abdulla, Sobranie, Embassy, Rothman, Dunhill, Silk Cut, Benson and Hedges, St. Moritz. Includes government health warnings. The 1898 item is an advertisement from the Graphic for Ogden's Guinea-Gold cigarettes.
    - Foreign advertisements for cigarettes, mostly 1990s (Box 69)
      Various languages, among them Arabic, Hebrew, Russian, and German. Brands include Merit, Parliament, Carlton, Chesterfield, L&M, Winston, Camel, Lucky Strike, Golf, Stuyvesant, Kent, Dunhill, R1, HB, West, Davidoff, Philip Morris, Players P&S, Craven "A", and others.
  - Other tobacco advertisements, Subseries 2
    See also oversize binder 56, and oversize binders 175-183.
    - Cigars, 1950s-1990s (Box 70)
      Magazine advertisements for brands of cigars and miscellaneous articles about cigars. Some German advertisements.
    - Loose tobacco and rolling papers, 1919-2001 (Box 71)
      Among brands represented are Three Castles, Old Holborn, Rizla (Riz la croix), Job (including copies of 19th century posters by Alphonse Mucha), ez-wider, Bambu, Prince Albert, Drum, Velvet. Some foreign advertisements. Collection includes some original packaging for tobacco and rolling papers. At the beginning of the notebook are yellow pages and classified advertisements for cigarettes.
    - Chewing tobacco and snuff, mostly 1980s-1990s (Box 72)
      Advertisements for tobacco products including Mail Pouch Tobacco, Skoal, Copenhagen snuff, Silver Creek, Timber Wolf, Rooster, Red Man, Redwood snuff, Granger, Kodiak. At the beginning, there is some material opposing chewing and snuff, including two pamphlets by the National Cancer Institute..
    - Cigarette pack design, cigarette girls, store displays, street ads, stadium ads, etc. (Box 73)
      Images are mostly from magazines and newspapers. Includes popular articles on advertising campaigns and copies of posters. Some material in languages other than English.
    - Cigarette cartons (Box 74)
      Original packaging for single packs of cigarettes and cartons for multiple packs of cigarettes. Various brands.
    - Philip Morris promotions, 1990s (Box 75)
      Gifts for taking the "Smokers Survey"; Virginia Slims Wear; Benson & Hedges Collection; Parliament; "Merit Awards."
    - Philip Morris promotions, 1990s-2000 (Box 76)
      Marlboro signs, gear, sweepstakes for travel, discounts.
    - "Camel Cash" and catalogs of Camel merchandise, 1990s-2002 (Box 77)
    - Catalog of Camel merchandise, 1998 (Box 78)
      Pages from a booklet of collectibles, including Joe Camel items, for Camel's 85th birthday.
    - R. J. Reynolds promotions; Moonlight Tobacco Co., 1990s (Box 79)
      Doral, Winston, Vantage, Salem, Kamel; Moonlight Tobacco Co. brands
    - Tobacco company sponsorship of auto racing, 1980s-1990s (Box 80)
      Images showing race cars and drivers sporting advertisements for cigarette brands, especially Marlboro; F1 race. Some German and Arabic.
    - Tobacco company sponsorship of auto racing, mostly 1990s (Box 81)
      Images and articles showing race cars and drivers advertising other cigarette brands. Includes some articles on tobacco company support of races, especially the Formula 1 (F1) race. Some German and Arabic.
    - Tobacco company sponsorship of auto racing teams and competitions, mostly 1990s (Box 82)
      Includes Indy 500 and F1.
    - Tobacco sponsorship of auto racing and competitions, mostly 1990s (Box 83)
      NASCAR Winston Cup Series; cars sponsored by a variety of cigarette brands.
    - Tobacco sponsorship of motorcycle races and other sports, 1976 and mostly 1990s (Box 84)
      Besides motorcycles, includes boat races, model race cars, golf, tennis, and basketball
    - Advertisements for duty-free cigarettes; various tobacco company promotions, mostly 1990s (Box 85)
      Gifts for taking a "Smoker's Survey"; Natural American Spirit promotional material; Lucky Strike signs, Kool Official Gear (for racing); Capri, Savannah, Newport
    - Older cigarette advertising images from the Web (Box 86)
      Includes early cigarette trade cards, Rameses, Melachrino, Egyptian Deities, Helmar, Murad, Omar, Fatima, Spud, Kool, Pall Mall, Tareyton, Raleigh, Lucky Strike, Camel, Chesterfield, Old Gold, Marlboro, Virginia Slims, Player's, Craven "A," and various other foreign brands. Some images are of items offered by e-Bay.
    - Outdoor advertising: Photograph album, Part I, mostly 1990s (Box 87)
      Photographs, presumably by William Van Duyn, of cigarette brands advertised on billboards, on taxis, and on other outdoor signs, as well as "No Smoking" signs and anti-smoking signs.
    - Outdoor advertising: Photograph album, Part II, mostly 1990s (Box 88)
    - Outdoor advertising: Photograph album, Part III, mostly 1990s (Box 89)
      Includes the Winston "no additives" campaign.
    - Outdoor advertising: Photograph album, Part IV, mostly 1990s (Box 90)
    - Outdoor advertising: Photograph album, Part V, 1998 October 20-1999 April 9 (Box 91)
      Includes some anti-smoking billboards, and some photographs of crushed cigarette pack litter.
    - Outdoor advertising: Photograph album, Part VI, 1999 April 9-2001 August 3 (Box 92)
      Cigarette advertisements; store displays; more tobacco carton litter, antismoking billboards.
    - Judge magazine, Smokers' Number, 1913 August 30 (Box 93)
      Photocopy of issue. Drawing of a woman smoking on cover; Pall Mall advertisement on back showing "Yale Gate."
    - Images of people smoking in advertisements for other products, 1940s-2000 (Box 94)
      Includes galleries, shows, restaurants and lounges, cars, clothing, food, drink, cosmetics, and travel.
    - Images of people smoking from magazine covers, posters (copies), and film and theater advertisements, 1949-2001 (Box 95)
    - History of tobacco; smoking in literature (Box 96)
      Excerpts of Georges Bizet, Carmen, Richard Klein, Cigarettes are Sublime; Ernest Hemingway, For Whom the Bell Tolls, Tom Robbins, Still Life with Woodpecker, Mark Twain, "Concerning Tobacco"; James Thurber, "The Catbird Seat"; Stephen King, Night Shift; John Grisham, Runaway Jury; and others.
  - Anti-smoking and tobacco politics, Subseries 3
    See also oversize binders 184-187.
    - American Cancer Society and American Lung Association anti-smoking promotions, 1980s-1990s (Box 97)
      Includes magazine advertisements, pamphlets, posters, signs, and stickers. Some of the ACS pamphlets feature Garry Trudeau's "Mr. Butts."
    - Anti-smoking pamphlets by the National Cancer Institute, National Foundation for Cancer Research, American Lung Association, and other organizations, mostly 1990s (Box 98)
    - Anti-smoking signs, anti-smoking advertisements, and articles, mostly 1990s (Box 99)
      Includes life insurance, smoking on airplanes, and some advertisements sponsored by the American Cancer Society and American Lung Association.
    - American Council on Science and Health anti-smoking reports, articles, and pamphlets, 1991-2000 (Box 100)
    - Tobacco politics and litigation, Part 1 -- newspaper and magazine articles, 1963-1996 (Box 101)
    - Tobacco politics and litigation, Part 2 -- newspaper and magazine articles, 1996-1997 (Box 102)
    - Tobacco politics and litigation, Part 3 -- newspaper and magazine articles, 1997 March 8-1997 June 20 (Box 103)
    - Tobacco politics and litigation, Part 4 -- newspaper and magazine articles, 1997 June 21- 1997 August 26 (Box 104)
    - Tobacco politics and litigation, Part 5 -- newspaper and magazine articles, 1997 August 25-1998 March 10 (Box 105)
    - Tobacco politics and litigation, Part 6 -- newspaper and magazine articles, 1998 March 11-1998 May 5 (Box 106)
    - Tobacco politics and litigation, Part 7-- newspaper and magazine articles, 1998 May 6-1998 August 15 (Box 107)
    - Tobacco politics and litigation, Part 8 -- newspaper and magazine articles, 1998 August-1999 April (Box 108)
    - Tobacco politics and litigation, Part 9 -- newspaper and magazine articles, 1999 April-2000 March (Box 109)
    - Tobacco politics and litigation, Part 10 -- newspaper and magazine articles, 2000 April-2001 December (Box 110)
    - Children and smoking, mostly 1990s (Box 111)
      Newspaper and magazine articles on smoking and children, especially teens. Includes discussion of bans on selling tobacco to children, "Mr. Butts," Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids, and advertisements from tobacco companies claiming to discourage children from smoking
    - Children and smoking, 1990s-2000 (Box 112)
      Materials on the campaign against marketing to children by INFACT, a Boston-based corporate watchdog; INFACT boycott of Kraft and Nabisco. Many of the materials were addressed to William Van Duyn.
    - "Opinion"--"Voices" from USA Today; columns by George Will, Ann Landers, Ask Beth, and Molly Ivins; miscellaneous other articles, 1936-1938, 1990s (Box 113)
      Includes articles from Fortune on Philip Morris, American Tobacco Company's Lucky Strike, and R. J. Reynolds, 1936-1938.
    - Popular science articles on smoking, cancer, and addiction, mostly1990s (Box 114)
      Some material at the end by the American Anti-Vivisection Society on the abuse of animals in smoking experiments.
    - Articles on the tobacco wars over federal regulation, mostly 1990s (Box 115)
      Some in Spanish.
    - Tobacco companies' public relations, 1930s-1990s (Box 116)
      Advertisements, especially from R. J. Reynolds, opposing new taxes on tobacco and "big government"; P. Lorillard advertisements against teen smoking; letters from tobacco companies to retail customers urging them to fight back; R. J. Reynold's "Survival Guide to the 90's"; copies of the Fortune article on R. J. Reynolds and on Lucky Strike, 1936-1938; postcards of Liggett & Myers and R. J. Reynolds headquarters and fields of tobacco, 1940s.
    - Philip Morris public relations, 1936-2000 (Box 117)
      Copy of Fortune article on Philip Morris, 1936; advertisements stating the company's position on smoking issues; Philip Morris' support of the arts; PM fight against hunger; PM advertisements to prevent underage smoking.
    - Issues of magazines featuring articles on the tobacco wars, 1995-2000 (Box 118)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960s-1990s (Box 119)
      Products to mitigate tobacco odor and teeth stains; obituaries of people who died from tobacco-related diseases; articles on the difficulty of quitting; secondhand smoke.
    - Miscellaneous, 1930s-1990s (Box 120)
      People smoking, cigarette marketing in Germany and Russia, "safer" cigarettes, sales of tax-free cigarettes by Indian tribes, parodies of cigarette warning labels, and more.
    - Smoking cessation system and product advertisements, mostly 1990s (Box 121)
      Includes Smokenders, EasyQuit, Phaseout, Quit Smart, hypnosis, acupuncture, Andre Passébecq, Bantron, Zyban. In some cases, William Van Duyn signed up to receive mailings.
    - Smoking cessation product advertisements, mostly 1990s (Box 122)
      Habitrol, Nicotrol, Merrell Dow (Lakeside Pharmaceuticals), Nicoderm, and Nicorette.
    - Websites: pro- and anti-tobacco, 1997-2001 (Box 123)
      Dowbloads of a detailed tobacco history from Tobacco.org, a history of Joe Camel, Friends of Tobacco (pro-tobacco), Badvertising Institute (anti-smoking), Americans for Nonsmokers' Rights, and others.
    - Websites: anti-tobacco, 2000 (Box 124)
      Truth (thetruth.com); Activist Massachusetts; ASH (Action on Smoking and Health (UK)).
    - Websites: tobacco companies, 2000 (Box 125)
      R. J. Reynolds, especially tests on the brand Eclipse; P. Lorillard.
    - Websites: Tobacco Manufacturers' Association (UK) and Gallaher group (UK tobacco company), 2000 (Box 126)
      Downloaded in 2000, but includes 1990s items.
    - Websites: British American Tobacco (UK) and the Imperial Tobacco Group (UK), 2000 (Box 127)
    - Website: dirtcheapcig.com, "The Last Refuge of the Persecuted Smoker", 2000 (Box 128)
- Oversize, Series II
  - Magazine advertisements for cigarettes by brand, Subseries 1
    - American Tobacco Company: Waterford, Bull Durham: Brown and Williamson: Richland, GPC, Carlton, Misty, Capri, 1966-1999 (Box 129)
    - American Tobacco Company: (Herbert) Tareytown, 1950-1973 (Box 130)
    - Brown & Williamson: Kool, 1930s-1980 (Box 131)
    - Brown & Williamson: Kool, 1980-2000 (Box 132)
    - Brown & Williamson (American Tobacco Company): Lucky Strike, 1918-1942 (Box 133)
    - Brown & Williamson (American Tobacco Company): Lucky Strike, 1942-1963 (Box 134)
    - Brown & Williamson (American Tobacco Company): Lucky Strike, 1964-2000 (Box 135)
    - Brown & Williamson: Pall Mall, 1935-1965 (Box 136)
    - Brown & Williamson: Pall Mall, 1965-1972 (Box 137)
    - Brown & Williamson: Viceroy, Twist, Kentucky Kings, Laredo, 1957-1975 (Box 138)
    - Brown & Williamson: Raleigh, Bel Air; American Tobacco Company: Montclair, Silva Thins: Maryland 100's, 1929-1973 (Box 139)
    - Liggett & Myers: Chesterfield, 1919-1944 (Box 140)
    - Liggett & Myers: Chesterfield, 1945-1992 (Box 141)
    - Liggett & Myers: L & M, 1954-1977 (Box 142)
    - Liggett & Myers: Fatima, Duke of Durham, Lark, Eve, Oasis, 1918-1975 (Box 143)
    - P. Lorillard: Newport, 1958-1999 (Box 144)
    - P. Lorillard: Embassy, Kent, Satin, Max, True, 1953-1990 (Box 145)
    - P. Lorillard: Murad, Old Gold, 1915-1972 (Box 146)
    - Philip Morris: Benson & Hedges, 1966-1998 (Box 147)
    - Philip Morris: Philip Morris and other brands, 1937-1992 (Box 148)
      Other brands include Multifilter, Saratoga, Players, Dave's, Spud, Paxton, and Alpine.
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1955-1967 (Box 149)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1968-1970 (Box 150)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1970-1979 (Box 151)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1981-1989 (Box 152)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1990-1996 (Box 153)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro, 1997-1999 (Box 154)
    - Philip Morris: Marlboro (international), 1969-1990s (Box 155)
      Advertisements from Great Britain and other countries.
    - Philip Morris: Parliament, 1958-1999 (Box 156)
    - Philip Morris: Virginia Slims, 1968-1999 (Box 157)
    - Philip Morris: Merit, Bucks, Basic, 1976-1999 (Box 158)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Camel, 1915-1937 (Box 159)
    - R .J. Reynolds: Camel, 1938-1945 (Box 160)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Camel, 1946-1957 (Box 161)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Camel, 1970-1997 (Box 162)
    - R. J. Reynolds. Camel, 1997-1999 (Box 163)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Kamel Red, Kamel Menthe; Moonlight Tobacco Co., 1996-1999 (Box 164)